Hello friends welcome back my name is Anil
and you are watching Anil Stock Educator today
in this video we will talk
about ICICI Lord General Insurance
before starting the video let me tell you that this will
not be any buying or selling tip it is
made only for educational purpose before starting the video
if you have not subscribed to the channel then let me
tell you that you should
subscribe as soon as possible so that such videos keep
reaching you so let's start
talking about general insurance
so
a few months ago I made a video about another insurance company it was
about ISI Prudential Life Insurance so you must check that out as well
I will put the link for you
if we talk about insurance company broadly then it is
divided into two categories life
insurance and non life insurance
we also call non life insurance general insurance so basically all the
categories other than life insurance
come under general insurance like
health health care insurance
car insurance bike insurance
marine various other types of insurance etc  We
go to property insurance etc.
etc. If we talk about ICCI Lombard,
they have a well diversified product mix. That means they
deal in all types of insurance. There is
a pie chart in front of you. You
can see that they have exposure to motor damage and third
party. Motor own damage and motor third
party are almost
more than 50%. This is a common
thing. If you look at any general insurance,
motor insurance has the highest
share of their revenue. Motor own
damage is at 28%, motor third party is at 23%.
After this, health and personal
accident is at 25%. Marine
insurance is also a small segment, it is
at 4%. However, you can see that and fire insurance also,
fire is at 12% and
others are at 8%. So, you can see the product mix
that this is the data of nine years.
So, you can see motor own damage and motor third party.
However, all these segments have
increased year on year. The company has increased its
product mix. So, motor own damage, for
example, in  If I tell you, it was 25 in 2018,
then it became 24 and now it
is at 28 for 2020, likewise you can refer others data here,
here you will find a catch
that crop insurance, you can see
that crop insurance was first at 19 in 2018,
then at 19 in 2019, sorry, it was at 19 in 2018, it became
17 in 2019 and became completely
negligible, so the company is showing a very cautious
approach here, I will
tell you more about it now, so
you all must be aware of the re-insurance segment in crop insurance,
when a company sells any insurance, then to
reduce its risk, it gets it re-
insured, that means
suppose a company has sold car insurance, suppose it is a
luxury car, it has taken insurance of Rs 50 lakh,
so if some problem occurs, then the
company will have to pay the entire Rs 50 lakh,
so what does the company do in that case  To
reduce the exposure, they get it re-insured, that is, there will be
some company too, after
paying some premium amount, and will say that
you can take the exposure at 25 or 50, so here the
company gets it re-insured by paying some premium again,
so what has
happened in crop insurance is that the re-insurance
terms and conditions have become unfavourable for the company
and I will tell you
how they are
increasing a lot, so this
business segment is not becoming viable for the company, so
due to this they have reduced the crop insurance rights,
so because of that you can see
that crop insurance has become almost negligible, there has been an
increase in all other sectors, whether we
talk about motor, third party own damage or health care, travel or fire,
marine, then there has been an increase in everything,
okay so let's talk about some
important parameters, revenue growth,
combined ratio, all are on the screen in front of you
in the form of a bar chart, so revenue growth
again you can see that in FY 2020 again it has
reduced  This has happened again because of
reduction in crop insurance, like I said,
so this has happened only and only because of crop insurance. If we
talk about combined ratio, then the
combined ratio has gone above 100 here,
which is not a good thing. The
lower the combined ratio, the
better it is. So, what is combined ratio basically?
I had explained this in the last video as
well. Still, let me give you a
brief description that
combined ratio means loss ratio
plus expense ratio. That means if the company is
earning whatever premium, say 00, it is
earning that premium by selling any policy
and it has to pay say 0 in the claim form, then
there the claim is made, I mean loss
ratio becomes 70 on 70 on 70 on
100, so 70 on, but
apart from the claim, the company has other expenses too.
Suppose salaries have to be paid, claim, I mean
claim settlement processing and commission have to be paid.
All the expenses incurred by agents are
called expense ratio.
So when we add up the loss ratio and expense ratio,
we get the combined
ratio. The lower the ratio, the
better. So, it should be less than 100%,
but here it is above 100%, it is 100.4. The
policy growth in the number of policies
sold has also increased. There has also been an
increase in claim settlement. So, let me
tell you that the claim
settlement ratio of ISI Ltd is 99.9. It is one of the best in the
insurance industry. If we
talk about investment assets, it is continuously increasing.
So, as you know, the company does
not earn only from premiums.
What insurance companies do is they
collect premiums from you and then
invest them in different assets like debt instruments, equity instruments, debentures, and
they earn returns from there too. So,
why does it become viable for the company here?
Because  Even if the combined ratio of the company is
going above 100, but if they
earn from investments there, then it gets covered up. If
you see the profit after tax for the company, it has reached
Rs 1.94 billion. Profit after
tax is growing steadily. Moving
on to solvency ratio, solvency ratio
tells how healthy your company is.
Meaning, here the regulatory requirement is
that the solvency should be
1.5. If
we look at the solvency ratio in percentage terms, it becomes 150,
but times, that is,
in the form of ratio, it should be 1.5. So if we
look at the data of FY 2020 whole year, then here it comes out to be
2.17 as on March 31, 2020.
Although this ratio has also increased. I will
tell you now that the company has also maintained return on equity
above 20. So it
is again a thumbs up on that part. If we talk about cash flow, then
here you will see that  The
company's cash flow from operations has
increased significantly from Rs 29 billion to Rs 4 billion. However,
if you look at the cash flow from investing activities and cash flow from financing activities,
both are negative because the
company is investing in investing activities. If we
talk about fiscal year 2020, the company had invested more in money
market instruments and liquid
mutual funds, hence
this number is negative.
Financing activities are negative
because the company had paid an interim dividend
in fiscal 2020. So,
if we talk about all-in-all net to net, the cash flow comes out to be
negative because you have spent more than the
cash flow generated from operating activities on
investing and dividend
distribution. So, here your net comes out to be
negative, Rs 3.69 billion
in negative. Okay, so some more data. So, here
some data is in front of you. Gross Direct
Premium Income. So, first of all, this is the first.  There are two columns
of data for a full year and both of these are half-yearly
data, so the first half of 2020 has been compared with the
first half of 2021, so
we are seeing a good number.
If I talk about gross direct premium income,
it means how much
premium are you writing,
how much premium are you collecting from your side,
how many policies are you collecting premium by selling,
so we call it
gross direct premium income, but
apart from direct premium, the company
also deals in re-insurance, so another
company, say, is getting re-insurance done
from ICICI Lombard, in that case also the
company gets some premium, so if
we add it up in GDPI, then
we get gross return premium,
so this is the same number, how much total premium did the company
collect by selling direct premium
and also by collecting re-insurance premium, so it is
called gross
direct premium, so if we talk about growth, then
17.2 percent of the financial year 2020
data is again negative,  This could be because
of slow down because there has been a slow down in motor insurance for the
last 3 years,
so due to that also it can be negative and if we
look at the data of financial year 2000, i.e. half year 2021, there is a growth of 8%
in GDPI, okay so like wise you combined
ratio, okay so combined ratio, I just
told you that it was 100.4, right, so see, it was
100.4 in financial year 2020, but now
it has become 99.8 in the first half,
so a good thing is that they have
reduced their combined ratio, profit
after tax has also grown well
from 10.49 to 11.9 and it has also grown in the first half,
from 6.18 to 8.14,
return on equity, I told you that it has
maintained above 20%, so
you can see in the first half it has become 24.9, it has
increased a lot, so the higher this ratio becomes, the more
we  We prefer,
but this ratio must be above 20.
Solvency ratio is 2.17, I told you that the age
on March 2020 was 2.74, but now this ratio has become 2.74,
so the company is improving health wise
here, so let's move on
to loss ratio, okay, so loss ratio, I
told you that in crop insurance, how the
company is incurring more and more losses, from that
you can see that the segment of crop,
2019-20 and then quarter and quarter, you
can also see how the
loss ratio in crop ratio, I mean crop, has been
very high, so here, keep in
mind that we are not talking about combined ratio, we are
talking only about loss ratio,
as I told that loss ratio can be 50, 60, 70,
80, depending on the
line of business that the company is dealing in,
okay, but here, if we talk about loss ratio
in crop insurance, then here  But the
loss ratio is becoming more than 100, which
means that if the company is collecting ₹1 as
premium, then the claim
itself is becoming more than ₹1. So,
apart from the add-on claims, the company is also incurring expenses
in paying commissions, salaries, etc.
So, if we look at that,
in the crop segment, we will see the combine ratio of the company very easily being
more than 120-130.
So, this is one of the reasons why the
company has reduced its exposure in crops.
If you look at all the other segments, the
maximum to maximum I am seeing was 84-90,
90 in motor third party.
Rest all are reasonable, the loss ratio of the company, I mean
loss ratio in all the segments. So, let's
talk about some more parameters,
if we compare the GDPI of FY20
excluding crop insurance, if
you see, if you neglect crop insurance,
in 2019, whichever
company  had collected premium, if you
remove crop insurance from it, then the
company has shown a growth of 10.5%,
but if you include crop insurance, then the
company has shown a growth of
88.1% because as I
told, the company has shown a cautious approach
here because losses are already being incurred there,
so what does it mean
if we talk about the growth of the right industry by taking exposure in crop insurance, then the
company has grown by 11.7% in 2020, whereas if we
talk from the beginning in 2001, when the
company came in 2000, that is, when the insurance
business of India was liberalized, it was
opened for the private sector,
you should know that before that
all the insurance companies were state
owned, that is, Government of India owned,
but after that, in 2000, the policy was changed by the
Government of India and the
insurance sector was
opened for private companies, so from there we
see that from 2001  There has been a CAGR growth of
16.7 percent in the general insurance sector
and if we talk about market share, then it is the
largest in the private sector.
In the private sector, we see that
ISI Lombard has a market share of 14.6 percent.
Overall, if we consider state-owned companies as
well, then
SCI Lombard becomes the fifth largest company here.
But
in the recent few months, there has been a development
that ISI Lombard is acquiring Indian Equifax,
so Indian Equifax has some market
share of around 1 percent. ISI Lombard has
received approval from all sides, from the Competition Commission of
India and the Insurance Regulatory and
Development Authority of India (NSC) and
BSCI.
So, in the coming days, we will
see that ICCI Lombard is acquiring Indian Equifax, which
means it will be merged,
so whatever is the portfolio of Indian Equifax will
come to ISI Lombard. So, here
we will see the market share of ICCI Lombard growing. So,
here the company I mean the company  It
is believed and experts believe that
after the company's total market share increases, the
company will become the third largest general insurer
in the overall general insurance market. Talking about debt, if
we talk about insurance companies, they are
generally debt free, like ASI, ISI,
Prudential Life Insurance, HDFC,
SBI. If we talk about any insurance company, then
those life insurance companies
are debt free, but ICI is not debt free.
They have debt of Rs 485 crore, but
if compared with equity, then it becomes
negligible because the debt to
equity ratio comes out to be 0.08. In other words, the
market share of industry
players is negligible. You can see that the
private sector has 48%, the public
sector has 39% and monoline
insurance has 13%. So, monoline insurance means
focused insurance,
like some insurance companies
focus only on the agriculture and culture segment,
some focus only on healthcare,
some on motor insurance, and
we call those companies monoline
insurance. So, let's talk about investments
that the company has  How much has been
invested? So, whatever the company has
invested, its asset value comes out to be
₹91.6 billion as on 31st
September 2020. So, the company
takes a cautious approach here also because you will see
that whatever money the company has at ₹84, it
invests in sovereign and triple A rated securities, meaning sovereign, you should
know that government
securities and triple A rated
securities, meaning some companies whose
rating is triple A, so the
company is investing in their bonds and debentures, so
there the company gets a good
return and the risk is also less
for the company. So, and because of that, the
analyzed return portfolio of the company
is ₹10.28, the company invests in equities
and the rest is
mostly invested in debt instruments.
So, here the equity
exposure on the company is less because again as a
result, the company takes a cautious approach,
hence it invests less in equities.
So, a good  The thing to know is that since the
beginning, when the company
started investing by collecting premium, there have been
zero instances of default. So,
you can see that the company invests only
in good companies, double A rated and triple A rated
securities, so by
investing there, the chances of your default become
negligible, hence the company has
not had any default till date, which means
that whichever company the company has
invested in, no one has defaulted till date.
Okay, and if we
talk only about the listed equity segment, then the
company has got an analyzed return of 23%.
If we talk about Nifty, then
Nifty has grown by 13.8% only. If we talk about
market share, then the market
share of the company ISI LRD is currently at 7.6%,
but it will
increase again from 0.5 to 2% after acquiring Bharti 1.
Okay, so if you look at it since 2015, the
market share has remained stable at 7 to 8%.  It has remained
stable between 85 and 100 per cent, neither has it decreased much
nor has it increased much, so here the
company will have to adopt some strategy as to
how to increase the market share.
Okay, so let's talk about
competitors. So here, from the side of four big competitors
from State and Government of India,
New India Assurance
is the market leader in general insurance. So, if we
talk about New India Insurance, then it has a
market share of 14 or 14.06 per cent.
Keep in mind that this data is of financial 2019,
so it is one year old. There
may be some ups and downs in this number here, but
I did not get the latest data, so
I am presenting the data of 2019 before you. So
according to that, New India Assurance
has 14.6 and United India Insurance has
99.63. Like wise, National
Insurance and Oriental Insurance, you
can see 7.9 and 98.92, after that, at
fifth number comes ICCI
Lumbarda, then Bajaj Allianz.  General
Insurance, ADAC, Tata, AAG, all these
companies are major companies of ISI Labad. So, let's
talk about the growth prospects,
what is the opportunity. So, if
we talk about India, then India is a
significant under-treated market
for general insurance and even for life
insurance sector. Well, okay, so if we
compare it with the US,
whatever premium is collected in USA,
that is, if we compare that with GDP, then
premium as a percentage of GDP will be
8.5 in the case of USA, but in the case of India,
it is again 0.94, but only if we
compare it with developed markets, then
this ratio turns out to be very low. So, from this
we come to know that, as it
came in the news a few days ago that
by 2000-25, India will be the fifth largest economy, then by
2030, India will become the third largest economy
after China and USA. So, the way
urbanization is taking place,  As the economy grows,
people will take more and more
insurance.
People will cover themselves more in health insurance. So, there is
potential for
growth in the insurance sector. At the same time, if we
look at the premium per capita, that is, if we take an average of premium per person, then it becomes
19 US
dollars. In the case of India,
okay, but if we compare it with USA and South
Africa, sorry South Korea, then
this number of $19 is very less
because in the US, you can see that it is
5000. If we talk about South Korea, then it comes out to be
around $500. So, we are still behind even countries
like Russia, Indonesia, Brazil.
Although our
economy is bigger than these countries, still
we are behind these companies in the insurance sector.
So, there is a big potential
for a big potential of growth for the
insurance sector in the years to come. Okay,
moving on to share holding pattern in our
last section of today's video. Okay, so if we
talk about promoters, then  The promoters
currently hold 51.8% shareholding. Let me
tell you that its promoter is ICICI Bank
itself, so the promoters have reduced their shareholding by about two and a half times in the recent past. If we
talk about FIIs, then FIIs are continuously
increasing their shareholding. If we talk about DIIs, then
DIIs are also increasing their shareholding. At the same time, if
we look at the public shareholding, then the public shareholding is decreasing.
So a surprising factor is that
our retail investors, which are
cheater pitter stocks like DHFL or
S Bank, whose
denomination has actually reduced a lot,
like there are stocks of ₹ 200,
but their quality has degraded a lot, so
they run away from there a lot. Whereas, in the
quality stocks,
their shareholding reduces.
If you compare it with DHFL, then
in DHFL you will see that
FIIs and DIIs are reducing their shareholding,
whereas the public is increasing their shareholding.
So what can we do about it?  Okay,
if I tell you about FIIs, then
614 FIIs have invested in ASI Labad,
whereas if we
talk about mutual funds, then 33 mutual funds have
invested their money in it, so friends, this is all
for today, I hope that
you must have got to know and learn something about the company,
watch the video till here.